黑暗
Darkness.
我最先记起的就是黑暗
That's the first thing I remember.
又黑又冷
It was dark, and it was cold.
我很害怕
And I was scared.
但就在那时
But then,
我看见了月亮
then I saw the moon.
那么大 那么亮
It was so big and it was so bright.
月光驱走了黑暗
It seemed to chase the darkness away.
当黑暗消失
And when it did,
我也就不再害怕了
I wasn't scared anymore.
我不知道自己为何出现
Why I was there and what I was meant to do,
应该做些什么
that I've never known.
我甚至怀疑自己永远不会知道
And a part of me wonders if I ever will.
你好啊 你好
Hello. Hello.
晚上好呀 女士 女士?
Good evening, ma'am. Ma'am?
噢 抱歉 能告诉我这是哪里吗?
Oh, uh, excuse me. Can you tell me where I am?
有人听到吗?
Hello?
我叫杰克冻人
My name is Jack Frost.
我是怎么知道名字的呢?
How do I know that?
月亮告诉我的
The moon told me so.
不过他只告诉过我这些
But that was all he ever told me.
那也是很久很久以前了
And that was a long, long time ago.
还在等着饼干呢!
Still waiting for cookies!
好了!
Yes!
啊 终于好了!
Ah, finally!
嗯! 不错
Mmm! Mmm.
我说过多少次要敲门了?
How many times have I told you to knock?
什么?
What?
"地球"出了问题?
The Globe?
走开 尖脑袋们
Shoo with your pointy heads.
你们干嘛总穿着防护罩?
Why are you always under boot?
怎么回事?
What is this?
检查过轴了吗? 自转平衡吗?
Have you checked the axis? Is rotation balanced?
会不会是?
Can it be?
小精灵们!
Dingle!
准备好吧
Make preparations.
我们的伙伴要来了
We are going to have company.
18颗中门牙
Eighteen central incisors.
莫斯科 第九区 22颗门牙 18颗前臼齿
Moscow, sector 9. 22 incisors, 18 premolars.
糟了 大雨警报
Uh-oh. Heavy rain advisory.
得梅因(美国爱荷华州首府) 枫树23区有颗乳牙 就位!
Des Moines, we've got a cusped at 23 Maple. Head out!
等等! 这是她的第一颗牙齿
Wait! It's her first tooth.
你们一生中 还有见过比这颗
Have you ever seen a more adorable lateral incisor
更可爱的侧门牙吗?
in all of your life?
瞧瞧它多洁白
Look how she flossed.
我的守护者伙伴们
My fellow Guardians,
我们的职责是守护全世界的孩子们
it is our job to watch over the children of the world
保护他们的安全
and keep them safe.
给他们带来奇迹 希望和梦想
To bring wonder, hope, and dreams.
今日我召集你们来此 只有一个原因
And so I have called us all here for one reason,
也是唯一的原因
and one reason only.
孩子们有难了
The children are in danger.
我们牵制了几个世纪的敌人
An enemy we have kept at bay for centuries
终于决心反击了
has finally decided to strike back.
只有我们可以阻止他
We alone can stop him.
啊 冻死了!
Oh, it's freezing!
哎呀 我脚都冻得没知觉了! 没知觉了!
Oh, I can't feel my feet! I can't feel my feet!
饼干? 蛋酒? 有人要吗?
Cookies? Eggnog? Anyone?
这次最好说正事 诺斯
This better be good, North.
沙沙 感谢你能来
Sandy, thank you for coming.
我知道 知道
I know, I know.
但是要不是事态严峻
But I obviously wouldn't have called you all here
我也决不会把你们都召集过来
unless it was serious.
嘘!
Shh!
食虫人来了! 来北极了!
The Boogeyman was here! At the Pole!
食虫人?
Pitch?
食虫人来这了?
Pitch Black? Here?
是的
Yes.
当时黑色沙砾笼罩了整个"地球"
There was black sand covering the Globe.
黑色沙砾是什么意思?
What do you mean, black sand?
然后出现了黑影!
And then a shadow!
等等 等等 你不是说看到食虫人了吗
Hold on, hold on. I thought you said you saw Pitch.
其实 也不算看到啦
Well, uh, not exactly.
"不算"? 这家伙能信吗?
"Not exactly"? Can you believe this guy?
是呀 你说对了 沙沙
Yeah. You said it, Sandy.
听好了 他肯定在策划什么阴谋
Look, he's up to something very bad.
我的肚子里
I feel it
有所感应
in my belly.
等会 等会 你是说 离复活节还有三天的时候
Hang on, hang on. You mean to say you summoned me here
你把我们召唤过来就是因为你肚子?
three days before Easter because of your belly?
老兄 要是离圣诞节还有三天的时候我这么对你...
Mate, if I did this to you three days before Christmas...
拜托了 兔子 复活节又不是圣诞
Please, Bunny. Easter is not Christmas.
开始说正事吧
Here we go.
诺斯 我可没时间闲聊!
North, I don't have time for this!
我还要涂完两百万个蛋呢!
I've still got two million eggs to finish up!
不管你再怎么涂 这依旧只是个蛋
No matter how much you paint, is still egg.
听好了 老兄 彩蛋的储存期很短
Look, mate, I'm dealing with perishables.
是吧? 圣诞礼物却能准备一年!
Right? You've got all year to prepare!
兔子为什么总这么紧张?
Why are rabbits always so nervous?
你为什么总这么爱吹牛?
And why are you always such a blowhard?
牙牙! 你没看到我们正要辩论吗?
Tooth! Can't you see we're trying to argue?
抱歉 不是所有人一年只需要工作一个晚上的
Sorry. Not all of us get to work one night a year.
我说得对吧 沙沙?
Am I right, Sandy?
圣地亚哥 2区
San Diego, sector 2.
别疑神疑鬼了 兄弟 食虫人已经和黑暗时代一同消失了
Come on, mate. Pitch went out with the Dark Ages.
我们都确定了
We made sure of it.
我知道就是他 我们情势危急啊
I know it was him. We have serious situation.
我倒是陷入了处理彩蛋的危机中
Well, I've got a serious situation with some eggs.
啊! 是月中人!
Ah! Man in Moon!
沙沙 你怎么不早说呢?
Sandy, why didn't you say something?
很久没见啦 老朋友
It's been a long time, old friend.
这次又有什么消息?
What is big news?
是食虫人
It is Pitch.
月中人 我们该怎么办?
Manny, what must we do?
嘿 伙计们 你们知道这什么意思?
Uh, guys, you know what this means?
他正在挑选一名新的守护者
He's choosing a new Guardian.
什么? 为什么?
What? Why?
肯定有大事 月中人认为我们需要帮手
Must be big deal. Manny thinks we need help.
我们何时起需要帮手了?
Since when do we need help?
我想知道会选谁!
I wonder who it's gonna be!
也许是小矮妖?
Maybe the Leprechaun?
千万别选土拨鼠 千万别选土拨鼠啊
Please not the Groundhog, please not the Groundhog.
杰克冻人
Jack Frost.
我收回刚才的话 土拨鼠其实不错
Uh, I take it back. The Groundhog's fine.
只要能帮忙保护孩子们就行 对吧?
As long as he helps to protect the children. Right?
杰克冻人? 他一点都不关心孩子们!
Jack Frost? He doesn't care about children!
是吧? 他只会不停冰冻水管
All right? All he does is freeze water pipes
然后捣乱我的寻蛋活动!
and mess with my egg hunts!
是吧? 他是个不负责任又自私的...
All right? He's an irresponsible, selfish...
守护者
Guardian.
杰克冻人可以做很多事
Jack Frost is many things,
但绝对做不了守护者
but he is not a Guardian.
呀! 啊!
Ya! Ugh!
噢! 这可真有趣啊
Oh! Now that, that was fun.
嘿 风儿!
Hey, wind!
带我回家吧
Take me home.
下雪咯!
Snow day!
噢! 冻住了!
Oh! It's freezing!
好爽!
Yeah!
哇! 哇!
Whoa! Whoa!
看起来挺有趣 好书吧?
Oh, that looks interesting. Good book?
好哟!  耶!
All right! Yeah!
下雪了!  下雪了! 真棒
Snow day! Snow day! Yeah.
不用谢啦
You're welcome.
嘿 兄弟们 等等! 这个礼拜天的寻蛋活动你们来吗?
Hey, guys, wait up! Are you guys coming to the egg hunt Sunday?
当然来了! 有免费的糖果呢
Yeah! Free candy.
希望雪这么大我们也能找到彩蛋!
I hope we can find the eggs with all this snow!
这上面说在密歇根找到了大脚怪的毛发样本
It says here that they found Bigfoot hair samples
还有DNA呢!
and DNA in Michigan!
很接近人类啊!
That's like super-close!
又来了
Here we go again.
你也看到视频啦 克劳德 他是存在的
You saw the video too, Claude. He's out there.
外星人你也说存在
That's what you said about aliens.
还有复活节兔子!
And the Easter Bunny!
复活节兔子是真实存在的
The Easter Bunny is real.
嗯 他确实是真的
Oh, he's real all right.
真的很讨厌 脾气真心坏 也真心自大
Real annoying, real grumpy and really full of himself.
拜托了! 你们这群人迟早会相信一切的
Come on! You guys will believe anything.
复活节兔子 跳啊 跳啊 跳!
Easter Bunny, hop, hop, hop!
哎哟!  老妈 苏菲又摔跤啦!
Ow! Mom, Sophie fell again!
你没事吧 苏菲?
You okay, Soph?
杰米 戴上帽子
Jamie, hat.
我们可不想让杰克冻人冻掉你的鼻子
We don't want Jack Frost nipping at your nose.
杰克冻人是谁?
Who's Jack Frost?
不是什么人 宝贝 只是个比喻
No one, honey. It's just an expression.
嘿!
Hey!
"谁是杰克冻人?"
"Who's Jack Frost?"
说吧 谁扔的?
Okay, who threw that?
肯定不是大脚怪啦 小屁孩
Well, it wasn't Bigfoot, kiddo.
啊!
Ahhh!
杰米・班尼特 你不合规矩!
Jamie Bennett, no fair!
是你先宣战的!
You struck first!
每人都免费来一发!
Free-for-all!
好吧 谁还需要雪球弹药?
All right, who needs ammo?
瞧啊!
Look at that!
糟了! 我打到了小蛋糕!
Crud! I hit Cupcake!
她打到了小蛋糕  你打到小蛋糕了?
She hit Cupcake. You hit Cupcake?
痛!
Ohhh!
是你扔的吗?  不是
Did you throw that? No.
也不是我!
It wasn't me!
哎呀 有点滑!  哦!
Oh, a little slippery! Ooh!
杰米 小心!  哇!
Jamie, watch out! Whoa!
滑到街上了  快停下! 有车!
That's the street. Stop! There's traffic!
哇! 别担心 杰米 我看着你呢 坚持呀!
Whoa! Don't worry, Jamie. I got you. Hold on!
肯定没事的!
It's gonna be all right!
跟上我吧 孩子! 左转咯!
Keep up with me, kid! Take a left!
嘿 慢点!
Hey, slow down!
停下 别 别 别这样
Hold up. No, no, no, no.
那是杰米・班尼特吗?
Is that Jamie Bennett?
这边请  不 别呀!
There you go. No, no!
哇!
Whoa!
天啊!  耶!
Oh, my gosh! Yeah!
哇 看起来挺严重啊  杰米 你没事吧?
Wow, that looks serious. Jamie, are you all right?
哇!
Whoa!
你们都看见了没? 太惊人了!
Did you guys see that? It was amazing!
我奋力一跃 然后滑着...
I did a jump and I slid under a...
哎呀
Whoops.
哦!
Oh!
太酷了! 一颗牙!
Cool! A tooth!
老兄 一颗牙就代表有钱咯!  牙仙的奖金!
Dude, that means cash! Tooth fairy cash!
不! 喂!  你看起来脏兮兮的!
Oh, no! Oh! You lucky bum!
我要把这个放到我枕头下面!
I got to put this under my pillow!
等一下 喂 等等 等等
Oh, wait a minute. Come on. Hold on, hold on.
我们刚刚那么开心算什么?
What about all the fun we just had?
又不是牙仙的功劳 是我!
That wasn't the Tooth Fairy, that was me!
我的耳朵都冻僵了!
My ears are freezing!
我要怎么做才能让你们小小注意到我?
What's a guy got to do to get a little attention around here?
有一长条雪痕
There was a patch of ice.
我不知道它是怎么出现的
I don't understand how it got here.
我是说 好歹复活节就快到了!
I mean, Easter is around the corner!
太棒了!
...it was awesome!
然后我从小坡上飞了出去
So then I was flying down this hill
飞快飞快地穿梭在车流之中
and it was like whoosh, whoosh, through these cars
然后雪橇撞到这个
and then the sled hit this thing
就像飞到空中一样!
and it was like way up in the air!
然后 砰得一声 沙发砸到了我...
And then, barn, the sofa hit me...
哇!
Wow!
瞧瞧 我的牙掉下来了!
...and see, my tooth came out!
好了 你把牙放到枕头下面了吗?
All right, you. Tooth under your pillow?
是的 准备好了
Yeah, I'm ready.
别熬夜想试图看到牙仙 杰米
Now don't stay up trying to see her, Jamie,
否则她是不会来的啦
or she won't come.
但是这次可以呀! 你想帮我吗 苏菲?
But I can do it this time! You want to help me, Soph?
我们可以藏起来偷看牙仙!
We can hide and see the Tooth Fairy!
好呀 藏起来 藏起来
Hide, hide, hide, hide.
不行 立刻上床睡觉 小伙子
Uh-uh. Straight to bed now, mister.
妈咪
Mom.
如果我做错了什么事
If there's something I'm doing wrong,
你可以告诉我我做错了啥吗?
can you just tell me what it is?
因为我已经尝试了所有办法
Because I've tried everything
却依旧没人能看到我
and no one ever sees me.
你把我丢在这里
You put me here.
至少你也要告诉我...
The least you can do is tell me...
为何把我丢在这
Tell me why.
很准时啊 沙人
Right on time, Sandman.
嗯
Mmm.
我觉得我听到了独角兽哒哒的马蹄声
Oh, I thought I heard the clippity-clop of a unicorn.
多么可爱的梦境啊!
What an adorable dream!
瞧瞧她
And look at her.
珍宝般的孩子
Precious child.
真甜美
So sweet.
充满了希望和奇迹
So full of hope and wonder.
然而 却仍缺少了一样东西
Why, there's only one thing missing.
就是一点恐惧
A touch of fear.
唔...
Mmm...
恐惧永不会衰老
That never gets old.
感受你的恐惧吧 来吧 来吧 就是这样
Feel your fear. Come on. Come on, that's right.
多么美丽的梦魇啊!
Yes, what a pretty little Nightmare!
现在
Now,
我要你去告诉其他人 等候期结束了
I want you to go tell the others the wait is over.
别这样看着我啊 老朋友
Don't look at me like that, old friend.
你肯定知道这一天终会到来
You must have known this day would come.
我的梦魇们已经准备就绪
My Nightmares are finally ready.
你的守护者们准备好了吗?
Are your Guardians?
哇!
Whoa!
你好啊 伙伴
Hello, mate.
很久没见了吧 我觉得68年的暴风雪之后就没见过
Been a long time. Blizzard of '68 I believe.
那天是复活节 对吧?
Easter Sunday, wasn't it?
兔子! 你不会还在为那事生气呢吧 对吧?
Bunny! You're not still mad about that, are you?
还气呢
Yes.
但这次是为了别的事来的
But this is about something else.
伙计们
Fellas?
嘿!
Hey!
放我下来! 干嘛呀...
Put me down! What the...
我?
Me?
当然不跟你们一起啦 北极见吧
Not on your nelly. See you back at the Pole.
哇!
Whoa!
他来了
He's here.
安静
Quiet.
嘿! 他来了!
Hey! There he is!
杰克冻人!
Jack Frost!
哇
Wow.
你开玩笑的吧
You got to be kidding me.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
放我下来  我希望这些雪人没有怠慢你
Put me down. I hope the yetis treated you well.
是呀
Oh, yeah,
我喜欢被塞到麻袋里 然后扔进魔法大门
I love being shoved in a sack and tossed through a magic portal.
那就好 是我让他们这么做的!
Oh, good. That was my idea!
显然你已经认识兔子了
You know Bunny, obviously.
很明显吧  还有牙仙
Obviously. And the Tooth Fairy.
你好 杰克 我听说过你不少事
Hello, Jack. I've heard a lot about you.
还有你的牙齿!
And your teeth!
我的什么?
My What?
张开嘴! 你的牙真有别人说的那么白吗?
Open up! Are they really as white as they say?
真的!
Yes!
真的像刚落下的雪花一样闪耀!
Oh, they really do sparkle like freshly fallen snow!
姑娘们 矜持点!
Girls, pull yourselves together!
不要给我们这身制服丢人
Let's not disgrace the uniform.
还有沙人
And Sandman.
沙沙?
Sandy?
沙沙? 醒醒!
Sandy? Wake up!
嘿 有没有人愿意告诉我 为什么带我来这里?
Hey, ho, anyone want to tell me why I'm here?
嘿 不懂你在说什么
Uh, that's not really helping,
不过还是谢了 小个子
but thanks, little man.
我肯定做了什么坏事 把你们四个都聚在一起了
I must've done something really bad to get you four together.
我是上了什么淘气名单吗?
Am I on the naughty list?
哈! 淘气名单呀?
Ha! On naughty list?
你一直是记录保持者
You hold the record.
不过不要紧 我们是高瞻远瞩的人
But, no matter. We overlook.
现在我们既往不咎了
Now we are wiping clean the slate.
怎么会这样呢?
How come?
啊 问得好
Ah, good question.
怎么回事? 我来告诉你怎么回事!
How come? I tell you how come!
因为你现在是守护者了!
Because now you are Guardian!
你在干嘛? 放开我!
What are you doing? Get off of me!
典礼开始!
This is the best part!
啥?
Huh?
你们怎么会认为我愿意当守护者呢?
What makes you think I want to be a Guardian?
你当然愿意了
Of course you do.
奏起音乐!
Music!
不许奏!
No music!
你们这也太谄媚了 不过我知道
This is all very flattering, but, uh,
你们根本不想要我
you don't want me.
你们都是勤劳的人 做事有底线
You're all hard work and deadlines,
我只会玩雪 到处享乐
and I'm snowballs and fun times.
我不是什么守护者
I'm not a Guardian.
是呀 这正是我说的
Yeah. That's exactly what I said.
杰克 我觉得你不明白我们的职责是什么
Jack, I don't think you understand what it is we do.
这里的每一个亮点都代表一个孩子
Each of those lights is a child.
一个有信念的孩子
A child who believes.
不管他们好还是坏 淘气还是听话
And good or bad, naughty or nice,
我们都会保护他们
we protect them.
啊! 啊!
Ah! Ah!
牙牙! 手拿开
Tooth! Fingers out of mouth.
哦 抱歉 它们太美了
Oh, sorry. They're beautiful.
好了 不说废话了
Okay. No more wishy-washy.
食虫人正在伺机而动!
Pitch is out there doing who knows what!
你是说食虫人?
You mean the Boogeyman?
对! 食虫人威胁着我们
Yes! When Pitch threatens us,
也威胁着孩子们
he threatens them as well.
所以你们该挑选个更加合适的人选
All the more reason to pick someone more qualified.
挑选? 你觉得是被我们挑选出来的?
Pick? You think we pick?
不 你是注定的! 跟我们一样
No, you were chosen! Like we were all chosen.
被月中人选定的
By Man in Moon.
什么?
What?
昨晚 杰克 他选中了你
Last night, Jack, he chose you.
可能吧
Maybe.
月中人... 他跟你们说的?
Man in the Moon... He talks to you?
是这样 你不能拒绝 这是命运
You see, you cannot say no. It is destiny.
那他为什么不亲自告诉我?
But why wouldn't he tell me that himself?
经过了300年 这就是他的答复?
After 300 years this is his answer?
让我跟你们一样长生不死
To spend eternity like you guys.
永远做一个隐形人 想方设法逗孩子们开心?
Cooped up in some hideout thinking of new ways to bribe kids?
不 不行 我不屑! 无意冒犯
No, no. That's not for me! No offense.
这还叫无意冒犯?
How is that not offensive?
知道我怎么想的吗?
You know what I think?
我觉得我们是徒劳的
I think we just dodged a bullet.
这个小丑
I mean, what's this clown
怎么知道如何给孩子们带去欢乐
know about bringing joy to children anyway.
呃 你听说过雪天吗?
Uh, you ever hear of a snow day?
没有煮老了的鸡蛋 不过孩子们喜欢我做的事情
I know it's no hard-boiled egg, but kids like what I do.
不过没人相信你的存在 对吧?
But none of them believe in you, do they?
你是隐形的 伙计
You see, you're invisible, mate.
跟不存在一样
It's like you don't even exist.
兔子! 够了
Bunny! Enough.
没事 这只袋鼠说得对
No, the kangaroo's right.
这只什么? 你叫我什么?
The what? What did you call me?
我可不是袋鼠 伙计
I'm not a kangaroo, mate.
哦 这么长时间我一直以为你是呢
Oh, and this whole time I thought you were.
你要不是袋鼠 是什么?
If you're not a kangaroo, what are you?
我是兔子 复活节兔子
I'm a bunny. The Easter Bunny.
人们相信我的存在
People believe in me.
杰克 跟我来
Jack. Walk with me.
不是有意的 诺斯
It's nothing personal, North.
不过你们做的事情 与我无关
But what you all do, it's just not my thing.
月中人说跟你有关!
Man in Moon says it is your thing!
会有结果的
We will see.
慢点 好吗? 我想溜进来很多年了
Slow down, would you? I've been trying to bust in here for years.
我要好好看看  你说 溜进来?
I want a good look. What do you mean, bust in?
哦 别担心 从来没过过雪人这一关
Oh, don't worry. I never got past the yetis.
哦 嘿 菲尔
Oh, hey, Phil.
跟上 杰克 跟上!
Keep up, Jack, keep up!
喔! 我一直以为玩具是小精灵做的
Whoa! I always thought the elves made the toys.
那是我们制造的假象
We just let them believe that.
很好! 好好干
Very nice! Keep up good work.
我不喜欢! 换成红色!
I don't like it! Paint it red!
大家 加油!
Step it up, everybody!
要水果蛋糕吗?
Fruitcake?
呃 不了 谢谢
Uh, no, thanks.
现在我们说正事
Now we get down to tacks of brass.
正事...
Tacks of...
你是谁 杰克冻人?
Who are you, Jack Frost?
你的内心是什么?  我的内心?
What is your center? My center?
如果月中人挑选你作为守护者
If Man in Moon chose you to be a Guardian,
你一定拥有与众不同的内心
you must have something very special inside.
嗯
Hmm.
你看
Here.
这就是你看我的形象 不对吗?
This is how you see me, no?
高大 威严
Very big, intimidating.
但如果再深入了解... 打开看看
But if you get to know me a little... Well, go on.
你是个开心果?
You are downright jolly?
不仅仅是开心果!
But not just jolly!
我还神秘
I am also mysterious,
而且无畏
and fearless,
富有同情心!
and caring!
而我的内心呢?
And at my center?
是个木头小娃娃
There's a tiny wooden baby.
仔细看 能看到什么?
Look closer. What do you see?
眼睛很大
You have big eyes.
对! 大眼睛 非常大
Yes! Big eyes. Very big.
因为充满着美好
Because they are full of wonder.
这就是我的内心
That is my center.
是我与生俱来的禀性
It is what I was born with.
我的眼睛能看到万事万物中的美好!
Eyes that have always seen the wonder in everything!
能看到密林中的光辉和空气中的奇迹
Eyes that see lights in the trees and magic in the air.
我把美好带给世界!
This wonder is what I put into the world!
把美好驻留在孩子们心中
And what I protect in children.
这就是我成为了守护者的原因
It is what makes me a Guardian.
这就是我的内心
It is my center.
你的呢?
What is yours?
不知道
I don't know.
有麻烦了 伙计 在牙仙宫殿
We have a problem, mate. Trouble at the Tooth Palace.
诺斯! 诺斯!
North! North!
我说了不跟你们一起了!
I told you I'm not going with you guys!
我才不要坐什么旧得快散架的...
There is no way I'm climbing into some rickety old...
雪橇?
...sleigh?
喔 喔 嘿!
Whoa, whoa, hey!
好吧 只坐一次 就一次好了
Okay. One ride, but that's it.
所有人都喜欢我的雪橇!
Everyone loves the sleigh!
兔子 你还等什么?
Bunny, what are you waiting for?
我觉得我的兔子洞会更快一些 伙计 而且更安全
I think my tunnels might be faster, mate, and safer.
呃! 进来!  喔!
Ugh! Get in! Whoa!
系好安全带!  喔 喔 喔
Buckle up! Whoa, whoa, whoa.
他妈的安全带在哪呢?
Where are the bloody seatbelts?
哈! 要安全带做什么 准备好了吗?
Ha! That was just expression. Are we ready?
好的 出发! 走!
Good. Let's go! Clear!
驾!
Yah!
别挡路!
Out of the way!
驾!
Yah!
哦 不!
Oh, no!
慢点! 慢点!
Slow down! Slow down!
希望你们喜欢过山车
I hope you like the loopty-loops.
希望你喜欢我吐的胡萝卜
I hope you like carrots.
走啦!
Here we go!
呜呼!
Whoo-hoo!
升空!
Blastoff!
喔!
Whoa!
哦...
Ohhh...
嘿 兔子
Hey, Bunny.
看这边
Check out this view.
诺斯! 他...
North! He's...
哦 你还是在意的
Aw, you do care.
哦 滚蛋 你个混蛋爱现鬼!
Oh, rack off, you bloody show pony!
大家 抓紧了! 走捷径了
Hold on, everyone! I know a shortcut.
哦 啊呀 我就知道应该走兔子洞的
Oh, strewth, I knew I should've taken the tunnels.
去牙仙宫殿
I say Tooth Palace.
驾!
Yah!
什么?
What?
哦! 喔!
Oh! Whoa!
这是什么?
What are they?
喔!
Whoa!
他们在抓牙仙!
They're taking the tooth fairies!
嘿 小牙仙 你没事吧?
Hey, little Baby Tooth, you okay?
给 你来开  啊?
Here, take over. Huh?
驾!
Yah!
他们在偷牙齿!
They're stealing the teeth!
杰克 小心!
Jack, look out!
牙牙! 你没事吧?
Tooth! Are you all right?
他们... 他们抓走了我的精灵
They... They took my fairies.
还偷走了牙齿! 所有的牙齿!
And the teeth! All of them!
全都没了
Everything is gone.
都没了
Everything.
哦 谢天谢地 还有一个没事
Oh, thank goodness. One of you is all right.
我要说 这确实 非常刺激
I have to say, this is very, very exciting.
四巨头 都到场了
The Big Four, all in one place.
我都被你们的星光晃晕了
I'm a little starstruck.
你喜欢我在"地球"上的表演吗 诺斯?
Did you like my show on the Globe, North?
把你们都招来了 是吧?
Got you all together, didn't I?
食虫人! 给你30秒把我的精灵们送回来!
Pitch! You have got 30 seconds to return my fairies!
不然怎么样? 你往我枕头下放个硬币?
Or what? You'll stick a quarter under my pillow?
你为什么要这样?
Why are you doing this?
可能是我想要你们拥有的
Maybe I want what you have.
想被人们相信
To be believed in.
我厌倦了躲在床下!
Maybe I'm tired of hiding under beds!
也许你就该在那里!
Maybe that's where you belong!
去找彩蛋吧 兔子
Go suck an egg, rabbit.
等等 那是杰克冻人吗?
Hang on. Is that Jack Frost?
你什么时候跟他们那么好了?
Since when are you all so chummy?
还没有
We're not.
哦 好的 中立方
Oh, good. A neutral party.
那我就无视你了
Then I'm going to ignore you.
不过估计你也早就被无视习惯了
But you must be used to that by now.
食虫人 你个躲躲藏藏的败类 过来!
Pitch, you shadow-sneaking ratbag, come here!
喔! 嘿! 放松 姑娘 放松
Whoa! Hey! Easy, girl, easy.
眼熟吗 沙人?
Look familiar, Sandman?
为了把梦境变成梦魇
Took me a while to perfect this little trick.
我花了不少时间去完善这项法力
Turning dreams into Nightmares.
别紧张
Don't be nervous.
这只会惹怒它们 它们能闻到恐惧
It only riles them up more. They smell fear, you know.
什么恐惧? 恐惧你?
What fear? Of you?
黑暗时代以后再也没人害怕你了!
No one's been afraid of you since the Dark Ages!
哦 黑暗时代
Oh, the Dark Ages.
所有人都心惊胆战 真悲惨
Everyone frightened. Miserable.
真是我的快乐时光 哦 我曾经的力量
Such happy times for me. Oh, the power I wielded.
可是月中人
But then the Man in the Moon
选择用你们的美好和光明来替代我的恐惧
chose you to replace my fear with your wonder and light.
温暖人们的心 带给人们希望
Lifting their hearts and giving them hope.
同时 所有人都把我当做噩梦挥之而去!
Meanwhile, everyone wrote me off as just a bad dream!
"哦 没什么可害怕的"
"Oh, there's nothing to be afraid of."
"根本就没有食虫人!"
"There's no such thing as the Boogeyman!"
哦 这一切都要改变了
Well, that's all about to change.
哦 看啊
Oh, look.
已经开始了
It's happening already.
什么?
What is?
孩子们开始醒来并且意识到
Children are waking up and realizing
牙仙并不存在了
the Tooth Fairy never came.
虽然是件小事 不过对于孩子来说...
I mean, such a little thing. But to a child...
怎么了?
What's going on?
他们... 他们不再相信我了
They... They don't believe in me anymore.
他们没有告诉你吗 杰克?
Didn't they tell you, Jack?
当守护者是很了不起
It's great being a Guardian.
不过有一个死穴
But there's a catch.
如果有足够的孩子不再相信
If enough kids stop believing,
你这些朋友守卫的一切
everything your friends protect,
希望 理想和美梦 都会消退
wonder, hopes and dreams, it all goes away.
然后一点一点的 守护者自己也会消失
And little by little, so do they.
没有圣诞节和复活节
No Christmas or Easter,
也没有夜晚到来的精灵
or little fairies that come in the night.
什么都没有 只剩下恐惧和黑暗
There will be nothing but fear and darkness.
还有我
And me.
该轮到你们不被相信了
It's your turn not to be believed in.
他走了
He's gone.
好吧 我承认
Okay, all right, I admit it.
你说的是真的
You were right about Pitch.
牙仙精灵们的事情我很遗憾
I'm sorry about the fairies.
你真该看看他们 他们那么奋力地抗争
You should have seen them. They put up such a fight.
为什么食虫人要偷走牙齿?
Why would Pitch take the teeth?
他要的不是牙齿
It's not the teeth he wanted.
要的是存在牙齿里的记忆
It's the memories inside them.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
这是我们收藏牙齿的原因 杰克
That's why we collect the teeth, Jack.
它们记录着儿时最宝贵的回忆
They hold the most important memories of childhood.
我和我的精灵们看护着它们
My fairies and I watch over them.
当有人需要记起什么最重要的时候
And when someone needs to remember what's important,
我们能帮助他们
we help them.
所有人的都有
We had everyone's here.
还有 你的
Yours, too.
我的记忆?
My memories?
当你还小的时候
From when you were young.
在你成为杰克冻人之前
Before you became Jack Frost.
可是成为杰克冻人之前我谁都不是
But I wasn't anyone before I was Jack Frost.
你当然是
Of course you were.
我们被挑选前 都是普通人
We were all someone before we were chosen.
什么?
What?
你真该看看那时候的兔子
You should have seen Bunny.
嘿 我告诉过你再也不要提了!
Hey, I told you never to mention that!
池塘的那晚 我只是... 我猜...
The night at the pond, I just... I assumed...
你是说...
Are you saying...
你是说在那之前我有自己的生活
Are you saying I had a life before that,
有家和家人吗?
with a home and a family?
你真的想不起来了?
You really don't remember?
这么多年 这答案就在这里
All these years, the answers were right here.
如果我们找回我的记忆 我就能知道我为什么会出现了
If I find my memories, then I'll know why I'm here.
你一定要告诉我!
You have to show me!
不行 杰克 食虫人夺走了牙齿
I can't, Jack. Pitch has them.
那我们必须抢回来了!
Then we have to get them back!
哦 不
Oh, no.
孩子们!
The children!
我们太晚了!
We're too late!
不! 不会的!
No! No!
没有太晚这回事!
No such thing as too late!
嗯...
Hmm...
等等 等等!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
啊?
Huh?
我们来收集牙齿
We will collect the teeth.
什么?
What?
我们收回来牙齿 孩子们就相信你了!
We get teeth, children keep believing in you!
我们说的可是七个大洲数以百万计的孩子!
We're talking seven continents and millions of kids!
得了吧
Give me break.
你知道我一晚能送多少玩具吗?
You know how many toys I deliver in one night?
我一天能藏多少彩蛋?
And eggs I hide in one day?
还有 杰克 如果你来帮忙
And, Jack, if you help us,
我们帮你找回记忆
we will get you your memories.
呃!
Ugh!
我加入
I'm in.
快! 快!
Quickly! Quickly!
快点 兔子! 我领先五颗牙了!
Hop to it, rabbit! I'm five teeth ahead!
听着 我要告诉你别碍我的事
Yeah, right. Look, I'd tell you to stay out of my way,
不过 那么 你又能怎么样呢?
but, really, what's the point?
因为不管怎样你都不能一直领先了
'Cause you won't be able to keep up anyway.
你想挑战我吗 棉尾巴?
Is that a challenge, cottontail?
哦 别想跟兔子比赛 伙计
Oh, you don't want to race a rabbit, mate.
比赛? 有比赛?
A race? Is it a race?
场面会很壮观的!
This is going to be epic!
这里有四颗乳牙! 两个街区以东有颗门牙
Four bicuspids over there! An incisor two blocks east.
那是颗臼齿吗? 到处都是! 哦! 噢!
Is that a molar? They're everywhere! Oh! Ow!
你没事吧?
You Okay?
抱歉 我没事
I'm fine. Sorry.
我已经很久没有到过现场了
It's been a really long time since I've been out in the field.
很久是多久?
How long is a long time?
440年 左右吧
440 years, give or take.
嗯
Hmm.
哈!
Ha!
啊哈!
Ahhh!
双胞胎!
Twins!
哦 头奖大礼包!
Oh, jackpot!
看起来你挺猛的 哈 伙计?
Looks like you're a bit of a brumby, eh, mate?
小菜一碟  喔!
Is piece of pie. Ow!
那是我的牙齿! 沙沙! 沙沙!
That's my tooth! Sandy! Sandy!
来了!
On!
喔 喔 喔! 别动手 老大
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Take it easy there, champ.
他是自己人! 欧洲的牙仙 对吧?
He's one of us! Part of the European division. Ca va?
哈?
Huh?
哈!
Ha!
哎呀!
Crikey!
漂亮!
Yes!
不!
No!
哈 哈哈
Ho, ho, ho.
哦! 你们收集牙齿留下礼物的速度
Wow! You guys collect teeth and leave gifts
像我的精灵一样快
as fast as my fairies.
你们记得留下礼物了 对吧?
You guys have been leaving gifts, right?
哈!
Ha!
这光明
The lights.
为什么还不熄灭?
Why aren't they going out?
他们在收集牙齿?
They're collecting the teeth?
安静不然我往你们笼子里塞个枕头!
Pipe down or I'll stuff a pillow with you!
好吧 最后再顽抗一下吧
Fine. Have your last hurrah.
明天
For tomorrow,
你们可悲的抵抗就将形同乌有
all your pathetic scrambling will be for nothing.
左门牙
Left central incisor,
在一次疯狂的雪橇意外中被撞掉
knocked out in a freak sledding accident.
我想知道怎么会发生这种事 杰克
I wonder how that could've happened, Jack.
孩子啊 是吧?
Kids, huh?
这一直是我最喜欢的部分
This was always the part I liked most.
看着孩子
Seeing the kids.
为什么我就是不能自已?
Why did I ever stop doing this?
嗯
Hmm.
在这么近看有些不同 对吧?
It's a little different up close, huh?
谢谢你能来 杰克
Thanks for being here, Jack.
真希望我能知道你的记忆
I wish I'd known about your memory.
我就能帮你了
I could have helped you.
对 是...
Yeah, well...
这样 先帮你
Look, let's just get you taken care of.
然后再去搞定食虫人
Then it's Pitch's turn.
你在这!
Here you are!
嘘!
Shh!
怎样 笨蛋?
What gives, slowpokes?
你感觉如何 牙牙?
How you feeling, Toothy?
被相信了
Believed in.
我就想听这个
That's what I want to hear.
哦 我知道了 你们结成一伙
Oh, I see how it is. All working together
让兔子得最后一名
to make sure the rabbit gets last place.
你觉得我想赢兔子还需要帮助吗?
You think I need help to beat a bunny?
看看吧 棉尾巴
Check it out, Peter Cottontail.
你那也叫一袋子?
You call that a bag of choppers?
这才是一袋子
Now that's a bag of choppers.
先生们 先生们 这都是为了帮牙牙
Gentlemen, gentlemen. This is about Tooth.
这可不是什么比赛
It's not a competition.
但如果是比赛的话 那也是我赢啦! 咦哈!
But if it was, I win! Yee-haw!
哦 不
Oh, no.
圣诞老人?
Santa Claus?
复活节兔子?
The Easter Bunny?
沙人?
Sandman?
还有牙仙! 我就知道你会来的!
The Tooth Fairy! I knew you'd come!
惊喜! 我们来了
Surprise! We came.
他能看到我们?
He can see us?
大多数
Most of us.
嘘! 伙计们 他还醒着
Shh! You guys, he's still awake.
沙沙 打晕他
Sandy, knock him out.
啊?
Huh?
用你的睡梦沙 你个二货!
With the Dreamsand, you gumbies!
不 别咬! 那是复活节的兔子!
No, stop! That's the Easter Bunny!
你要干什么 阿比? 坐下!
What are you doing, Abbey? Down!
好了 全都别慌
All right, nobody panic.
但那是一只猎犬
But that's a greyhound.
你知道猎犬是怎么对付兔子的吗?
Do you know what greyhounds do to rabbits?
我敢肯定它从来没见过我这样的兔子
I think it's a pretty safe bet he's never met a rabbit like me.
一米八五的身高
Six-foot-one,
还有钢铁般的意志
nerves of steel.
太极拳大师 古代艺术的...
Master of tai-chi and the ancient art of...
哎呀!
Crikey!
别跑! 坐下!
Stop! Sit!
坐下 乖女孩 坐下!
Down, girl, down!
哇哦!
Whoa!
沙沙!
Sandy!
她很狂躁! 让这澳洲野狗离我远点!
She's rabid! Get this dingo off me!
哦 不
Oh, no.
拐杖糖...
Candy canes...
哇哦!
Whoa!
真糟
Whoops.
哦 我真希望现在有部照相机
Oh, I really wish I had a camera right now.
沙沙 快来! 我们去找食虫人!
Sandy, come on! We can find Pitch!
漂漂
Pretty.
小兔子 蹦 蹦 跳!
Bunny, hop, hop. Hop!
哦!
Ooh!
哎哟!
Ow!
什么... 哈?
What... Huh?
呜哦!
Whoo!
真爽!
Yes!
我冻住它了
I got it.
沙沙!
Sandy!
沙沙 你看到了吗?
Sandy, did you see that?
看看这个东西
Look at this thing.
杰克冻人?
Frost?
要知道 作为中立方
You know, for a neutral party,
你跟那些怪咖在一起的时间过多了
you spend an awful lot of time with those weirdos.
这不是你的战斗 杰克
This isn't your fight, Jack.
你偷了那些牙齿的时候就把我牵扯进来了!
You made it my fight when you stole those teeth!
牙齿? 你干嘛在乎那些牙齿?
Teeth? Why do you care about the teeth?
这才是我要找的人
Now this is who I'm looking for.
这倒提醒我了 千万不能跟你作对
Remind me not to get on your bad side.
好了 放松点 我就想试试 你别怪我 沙沙
Okay, easy. You can't blame me for trying, Sandy.
你不知道虚弱又被人恨的感觉是怎样的
You don't know what it's like to be weak and hated.
我真是太笨了 竟然想扰乱你的美梦
It was stupid of me to mess with your dreams.
所以 这么办吧
So, I'll tell you what.
你可以把它们拿回去
You can have them back.
你对付左边的
You take the ones on the left,
我对付右边的?
I'll take the ones on the right?
出击!
Boo!
哈?
Huh?
来吧!
Come on!
你最好弯腰躲一下
You might want to duck.
我们得帮帮沙沙!
We've got to help Sandy!
呀!
Yah!
不!
No!
杰克!
Jack!
不要跟恐惧作对 小个子!
Don't fight the fear, little man!
快点! 快点 杰克!
Hurry! Hurry, Jack!
我想说"做个好梦" 可是美梦已不复存在了
I'd say "Sweet dreams," But there aren't any left.
沙沙?
Sandy?
不!
No!
杰克!
Jack!
杰克 你是怎么做到的?
Jack, how did you do that?
我都不知道自己有这力量
I didn't know I could.
终于!
Finally!
出现了一个可以玩玩的人了!
Someone who knows how to have a little fun!
你还好吗?
Are you all right?
我只是...
I just...
我希望当时能做点什么
I wish I could've done something.
做点什么?
Done something?
杰克 你勇敢地抵抗了食虫人 你救了我们!
Jack, you stood up to Pitch. You saved us!
可是沙沙...
But Sandy...
他会为你的举动骄傲的
Would be proud of what you did.
我不知道你的前世是怎样的
I don't know who you were in your past life.
但在今生 你是名守护者
But in this life, you are Guardian.
但不知道过往 我怎能了解现在的自己?
But how can I know who I am until I find out who I was?
你会的
You will.
我感觉得到
I feel it
我的肚子告诉我的
in my belly.
看这些灯灭得多快
Look how fast they're going out.
是恐惧
It's fear.
平衡已被打破
He's tipped the balance.
嘿 打起精神 你们这些糊涂蛋!
Hey, buck up, you sad sacks!
我们还可以扭转战局!
We can still turn this around!
明天就是复活节
Easter is tomorrow.
我需要你们的帮助 只要我们全力以赴
And I need your help. I say we pull out all the stops
就能让这些小光点们再次闪动
and we get those little lights flickering again.
兔子说得对
Bunny is right.
老朋友 尽管这么说让我很痛心
As much as it pains me to say, old friend,
这次 复活节远比圣诞节重要
this time, Easter is more important than Christmas.
嘿 大伙儿听到了吗?
Hey, did everyone hear that?
我们必须赶快到兔子洞 各位! 上雪橇!
We must hurry to the warren. Everyone! To the sleigh!
哦 不 伙计 我的兔子洞我作主 系好安全带
Oh, no, mate. My warren, my rules. Buckle up.
完蛋了!
Shostakovich!
哦!
Oh!
"系好安全带" 太好玩了
"Buckle up." Is very funny.
欢迎来到兔子洞
Welcome to the warren.
有情况
Something's up.
苏菲吗?
Sophie?
精灵 精灵 小精灵!  她在这干嘛?
Elf, elf, elf! What is she doing here?
我丢了雪景球
Ah, snow globe.
该死! 快点想办法
Crikey! Somebody do something.
哦 别看我 她看不见我 记得吗?
Oh, don't look at me. I'm invisible, remember?
小精灵! 小精灵!
Elf! Elf!
别担心 兔子 我打赌她是仙女迷
Don't worry, Bunny. I bet she's a fairy fan.
没事 小家伙  漂漂
It's okay, little one. Pretty.
哦! 知道吗? 我有东西给你!
Oh! You know what? I've got something for you!
在这里!
Here it is!
看这些漂亮的牙齿
Look at all the pretty teeth,
上面还有血和牙龈呢!
with little blood and gum on them!
血和牙龈?
Blood and gums?
你们最后一次和孩子们玩耍
When was the last time
都是什么时候的事了?
you guys actually hung out with kids?
躲猫猫!
Peek-a-boo!
我们忙于把快乐带给孩子们
We are very busy bringing joy to children.
我们没有时间...
We don't have time...
陪孩子们玩了  嗯
For children. Hmm.
如果一个小屁孩就能毁了复活节
If one little kid can ruin Easter,
那我们的处境比我想的糟多了
then we're in worse shape than I thought.
你想画蛋吗? 想吗?
You want to paint some eggs? Yeah?
好的  来吧
Okay. Come on.
壮观!
Rimsky-Korsakov!
真是很多蛋啊
That's a lot of eggs.
呃 我们还有多少时间?
Uh, how much time do we have?
好了 大军 是时候反击了
All right, troops, it's time to push back.
让彩蛋遍布全球!
That means eggs everywhere!
你们要成堆出现在每栋高楼
Heaps of you in every high-rise,
农场 还有活动房屋里!
farmhouse, and trailer park!
还有网球鞋和早餐碗里
In tennis shoes and cereal bowls.
哦 还有五彩糖果浴!
Oh, there will be bathtubs filled with my beautiful googies!
好吧 这颜色有点怪
Okay, that's a little strange.
不 伙计
No, mate.
这很可爱
That's adorable.
这会是春天! 降临每块大陆!
There will be springtime! On every continent!
我会将希望带给大家!
And I'm bringing hope with me!
太圣诞节了 伙计 把它们涂成蓝色
Too Christmas-y, mate. Paint them blue.
哦 那个是什么?
Oh, what's over there?
真是颗漂亮的彩蛋!
Oh, that's a beauty!
现在 我们只要把他和他的小伙伴们
Now, all we got to do is get him and his little mates
通过地下通道送到地面
through the tunnels to the top
复活节就来临了
and we'll have ourselves Easter.
干得不错
Not bad.
你干得不错
Not bad yourself.
听着 我很抱歉...
Look, I'm sorry about the whole...
你知道的 说你是袋鼠的事
You know, the kangaroo thing.
是口音的问题 对吧?
It's the accent, isn't it?
哦 可怜的小家伙 看看她 都累坏了
Oh, poor little ankle-biter. Look at her. All tuckered out.
我好爱她
I love her.
我想该送她回家了
I think it's time to get her home.
我送她回家怎么样?
How about I take her home?
杰克 不行 食虫人他...  他的力量不如我
Jack, no. Pitch is... No match for this.
所以我们需要你在身边
Which is why we need you here with us.
相信我 我会像兔子一样快的
Trust me. I'll be quick as a bunny.
哦
Ooh.
苏菲? 是你吗?
Sophie? Is that you?
我们该回去了
We should get back.
杰克!
Jack!
这声音 我记得这声音
That voice, I know that voice.
杰克!
Jack!
别担心 还有时间
Don't worry, there's still time.
杰克?
Jack?
小牙仙 别闹!
Baby Tooth, come on!
我得找到那是什么声音
I have to find out what that is.
嘘! 别出声!
Shh! Keep it down!
我马上带你们出去 只要我...
I'm gonna get you out of here just as soon as...
杰克?
Jack?
杰克!
Jack!
找到办法
...as I can.
在找什么东西吗?
Looking for something?
别害怕 杰克 我不会伤害你的
Don't be afraid, Jack. I'm not gonna hurt you.
害怕? 我可不怕你
Afraid? I'm not afraid of you.
或许不 但你在害怕别的事情
Maybe not. But you are afraid of something.
你竟然这样想?  我知道就是这样!
You think so, huh? I know so!
一直以来我都很清楚
It's the one thing I always know.
人类最大的恐惧
People's greatest fears.
你的就是永远没有人会相信你
Yours is that no one will ever believe in you.
而且最糟糕的是 你害怕自己永远不知道原因
And worst of all, you're afraid you'll never know why.
为什么是你?
Why you?
为什么要选你做守护者?
Why were you chosen to be like this?
不过不用害怕
Well, fear not.
因为答案就在这里
For the answer to that is right here.
你想要吗 杰克? 你的记忆?
Do you want them, Jack? Your memories?
你想知道的一切 都在这个小盒子里
Everything you wanted to know, in this little box.
你为什么会变成这样? 别人看不到你
Why did you end up like this? Unseen.
不能接触任何人
Unable to reach out to anyone.
你太想知道答案了 你想抓住它们
You want the answers so badly. You want to grab them
然后私自飞走 但你害怕
and fly off with them. But you're afraid
其他守护者会怎么想
of what the Guardians will think.
你害怕让他们失望
You're afraid of disappointing them.
好了 让我帮你搞清一件事
Well, let me ease your mind about one thing.
他们永远都不会真心接纳你的 永远不会
They'll never accept you. Not really.
住嘴!
Stop it!
别说了!
毕竟 你不是他们中的一员
After all, you're not one of them.
你不知道我是谁
You don't know what I am.
我当然知道! 你是杰克冻人
Of course I do! You're Jack Frost.
你所到之处一片狼藉
You make a mess wherever you go.
为什么 因为你现在就是这样
Why, you're doing it right now.
你做了什么?
What did you do?
杰克 更重要的是你做了什么?
More to the point, Jack, what did you do?
小牙仙!
Baby Tooth!
复活节快乐 杰克
Happy Easter, Jack.
不
No.
这儿没有彩蛋
There aren't any eggs.
这儿什么都没有  我放弃了
There's nothing here. I give up.
他没来  我不明白
He didn't come. I don't understand.
或许他只是今年藏得特别好
Maybe he just hid them really well this year.
孩子们!  我都找遍了 什么都没有
Kids, oh! I checked everywhere. There's nothing.
有的 在这儿! 在这儿!
Yes, there is! There is!
我知道 这不是我最好看的彩蛋
I mean, these aren't my best looking googies,
但在紧要关头也能凑合
but they'll do in a pinch.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我知道
I know.
根本就没有复活节兔子
There's no such thing as the Easter Bunny.
什么? 不
What? No.
错了! 不是的!
Wrong! Not true!
我就在你们面前 孩子们  为什么他不来?
I'm right in front of you, mate. Why wouldn't he come?
他们看不到我
They don't see me.
他们看不到我了
杰克 你去哪了?
Jack, where were you?
噩梦已经侵入了地下洞
The Nightmares attacked the tunnels.
他们砸碎了每只蛋 压碎了每只篮子
They smashed every egg, crushed every basket.
没有一只蛋安全到达地面
Nothing made it to the surface.
杰克
Jack.
你从哪拿的那个?
Where did you get that?
我... 这是...
I was... It's...
小牙仙在哪?
Where's Baby Tooth?
哦 杰克 你做了什么?
Oh, Jack, what have you done?
这是你没回来的原因?
That is why you weren't here?
你和食虫人在一起?
You were with Pitch?
不 听我说 听我说
No, listen, listen.
我很抱歉 我不是有意这样的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean for this to happen.
他必须离开  什么?
He has to go. What?
我们就不该相信你的!
We should never have trusted you!
复活节是新的开始 新的生活
Easter is new beginnings, new life.
复活节是希望的象征
Easter's about hope.
现在一切都没了
And now it's gone.
哇哦! 哇哦 哇哦!
Whoa! Whoa, whoa!
啊!
Aah!
我们再翻一遍公园吧
Let's check the park again.
真的吗?  为了什么? 复活节兔子?
Really? For what? The Easter Bunny?
大伙儿 我说了 我看到他了!
Guys, I told you, I saw him!
他比我想象的大很多
He's way bigger than I thought
而且他还有很酷的回旋镖什么的!
and he's got these cool boomerang things!
成熟点吧 杰米  哦 伙计 开玩笑的吧?
Grow up, Jamie. Oh, man. Seriously?
你们到底怎么了?
What's happened to you guys?
那是梦而已!
It was a dream!
你应该开心还能有那样的梦
You should be happy you still get dreams like that
而不是...
and not...
噩梦
Nightmares.
算了吧 杰米
Forget it, Jamie.
今年就是没有复活节了
There's just no Easter this year.
他的确是真的!
He really is real!
我知道他是
I know he is.
我就知道会变成这样
I thought this might happen.
他们从没有真的信任过你
They never really believed in you.
我只是想帮你证实这点
I was just trying to show you that.
但是我了解你的心情
But I understand.
你什么都不了解!
You don't understand anything!
不了解? 我不知道被驱逐的滋味吗?
No? I don't know what it's like to be cast out?
不被相信的滋味?
To not be believed in?
渴望家庭的滋味
To long for a family.
在阴影里那么多年 我认为
All those years in the shadows I thought
没人比我更清楚这种感觉
no one else knows what this feels like.
但现在我知道自己错了
But now I see I was wrong.
我们不必孤身一人 杰克
We don't have to be alone, Jack.
我相信你 我知道孩子们也会相信的
I believe in you. And I know children will, too.
相信我?
In me?
是的!
Yes!
看看我们的能力吧
Look at what we can do.
还有什么比寒冷和黑暗结合更强大的?
What goes together better than cold and dark?
我们可以让他们相信
We can make them believe.
我们可以给他们一个世界 那里的一切都是...
We'll give them a world where everything, everything is...
食虫人吗?
Pitch black?
还有杰克冻人
And Jack Frost, too.
他们都会相信我们两个
They'll believe in both of us.
不 他们会害怕我们两个 而那不是我想要的
No, they'll fear both of us. And that's not what I want.
现在最后警告你一次
Now for the last time,
离我远点
leave me alone.
非常好 你想不被人打扰 可以 但首先...
Very well. You want to be left alone. Done. But first...
小牙仙!
Baby Tooth!
把拐杖给我 杰克!
The staff, Jack!
你有个多管闲事的坏习惯
You have a bad habit of interfering.
现在把冰杖给我 我就放了她
Now, hand it over, and I'll let her go.
好了
All right.
现在放了她
Now let her go.
不
No.
你刚才说你想独自一个人
You said you wanted to be alone.
那就一个人吧!
So be alone!
不要!
No!
小牙仙!
Baby Tooth!
你没事吧?
You all right?
对不起 我只有让你挨冻的份
Sorry. All I can do is keep you cold.
食虫人说得对
Pitch was right.
我把事情搞得一塌糊涂
I make a mess of everything.
嘿
Hey.
杰克?
Jack?
杰克!
Jack!
哦!
Oh!
杰克!
Jack!
回来 杰克
Come on, Jack,
你不能总玩
you can't have fun all the time.
杰克 从上面下来
Jack, get down from there.
杰克!  你真好玩 杰克
Jack! You're funny, Jack.
小心点
Be careful.
会的
We will.
没事 没事
It's okay. It's okay.
不要往下看 看着我
Don't look down. Just look at me.
杰克
Jack.
我害怕
I'm scared.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
但你不会有事的 你不会掉下去的
But you're gonna be all right. You're not gonna fall in.
我们来玩些好玩的!
We're gonna have a little fun instead!
不可能!
No, we're not!
我会骗你吗?
Would I trick you?
会呀! 你老是骗我!
Yes! You always play tricks!
好吧
All right.
但这次没骗你
Well, not this time.
我保证 我保证 你...
I promise, I promise. You're gonna be...
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
你必须相信我
You have to believe in me.
想玩游戏吗? 我们来玩跳房子!
You want to play a game? We're gonna play hopscotch!
就跟我们平时玩的一样
Like we play every day.
很简单
It's as easy as
一...
one...
哇!
Whoa!
二
Two.
三!
Three!
好了
All right.
该你了
Now it's your turn.
一...
One...
很棒 很棒
That's it, that's it.
二
Two.
三!
Three!
啊!
Whoa!
杰克!
Jack!
你... 你看见了吗?
Did you see... Did you see that?
是我!
It was me!
我有个家! 有个妹妹!
I had a family! I had a sister!
我还救了她!
I saved her!
这是你选我的原因吧
That's why you chose me.
我是个守护者
I'm a Guardian.
我们得离开这儿
We have to get out of here.
好吧
Okay.
我们走 小牙仙 我欠你个人情!
Come on, Baby Tooth, I owe you one!
快! 我们走!
Come on! Let's go!
怎么了?
What's wrong?
你们都不能飞了?
None of you can fly?
那些光点
The lights.
你们可以下岗了!
You're all free to go!
孩子们今年不需要圣诞玩具了
We won't be needing any Christmas toys this year,
谢谢
thank you.
以后都不需要了
Nor ever again.
光点都灭了
They're all going out.
只留下六个孩子
Only six left.
六个宝贵的孩子
Six precious children
仍然死心塌地相信守护者
who still believe in the Guardians with all their hearts.
现在只剩下
Make that
五个
five.
哦!
Oh!
四个
Four.
三个!
Three!
两个!
Two!
一个
One.
杰米
Jamie.
听着
Okay, look.
你和我显然到了人们所说的人生分叉口
You and I are obviously at what they call a crossroads.
所以我们这么办吧
So here's what's gonna happen.
如果守护者不是骗人的 你真的存在
If it wasn't a dream and if you are real
你必须证明 现在就证明
then you have to prove it, like, right now.
我相信你很长时间了 对吧?
I've believed in you for a long time, okay?
事实上 我一直都相信你
Like, my whole life, in fact.
所以你多少欠我一个人情
So you kind of owe me now.
不需要太麻烦 给我一点点示意让我知道你存在
You don't have to do much. Just a little sign so I know.
做什么都行
Anything.
什么都行
Anything at all.
我就知道
I knew it.
他是真的!
He's real!
哇哦!
Whoa!
雪?
Snow?
杰克冻人
Jack Frost.
他刚才说...
Did he just say...
杰克冻人?
Jack Frost?
他又说了 他说...
He said it again. He said...
你说...
You said...
杰克冻人!
Jack Frost!
没错!
That's right!
就是我! 杰克冻人! 这是我的名字!
But that's me! Jack Frost! That's my name!
你刚才叫了我的名字!
You said my name!
等等 你能听到我说话?
Wait. Can you hear me?
你能...
Can you...
你能看见我?
Can you see me?
他能看见我! 他能看见我!
He sees me! He sees me!
刚才是你下的雪!  是啊!
You just made it snow! I know!
在我的房间!  没错!
In my room! I know!
你真的存在?  对呀!
You're real? Yeah!
除了我还有谁会在你的房间下雪啊?
Who do you think brings you all the blizzards and the snow days?
你还记得那天你坐着雪橇上飞吗?
And you remember when you went flying on that sled the other day?
原来是你?  正是!
That was you? That was me!
酷!  是吧?
Cool! Right?
那复活节兔子和牙仙是真的吗?
But what about the Easter Bunny? And the Tooth Fairy?
真的 真的! 我们都是真的
Real, real, real! Every one of us is real.
我就知道!
I knew it!
杰米 你在和谁说话?
Jamie, who are you talking to?
嗯...
Um...
杰克冻人?
Jack Frost?
好吧
Okay.
喔 喔 小心!
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa!
我的孩子们! 回来!
Ah, moi deti! Come back!
诺斯 你没事吧?  现在可以明确告诉你
North, are you okay? Is official.
我的魔法失灵了
My powers are kaput.
看!
Look!
杰克!
Jack!
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
你在这干什么?
What are you doing here?
和你们一样
Same as you.
最后的光点
The last light.
哇 是你! 竟然是你!
Wow. It is you! I mean, it is you!
我就知道你们是真的!
I knew it wasn't a dream!
杰克 他能看见你
Jack, he sees you.
对了 兔子哪去了?
Wait. But where's Bunny?
复活节计划的失败给我们造成很大损失
Losing Easter took its toll on all of us.
尤其是对兔子
Bunny most of all.
不会吧
Oh, no.
他就是复活节兔子?
That's the Easter Bunny?
总算有人看见我了!
Now somebody sees me!
你一小时前干什么呢 伙计?
Where were you about an hour ago, mate?
他怎么了?
What happened to him?
他以前高大威猛 但现在变成了...
He used to be huge and cool. And now he's...
小可爱
Cute.
很好
Oh, that's good.
这是你教他说的吗? 肯定是!
Did you tell him to say that? That's it!
来吧! 我们较量一下! 来!
Let's go! Me and you! Come on!
不 事实上 他告诉我你是真的
No. Actually, he told me you were real.
我差点认为你是骗人的
Just when I started to think that maybe you weren't.
他让你相信了?
He made you believe?
我?
In me?
保护杰米离开这
Get Jamie out of here.
小心点 杰克
Be careful, Jack.
杰克冻人
Jack Frost.
我们是不是该做个了断了?
Let's end this, shall we?
啊!
Aah!
这点小把戏对我没用了
That little trick doesn't work on me anymore.
这边 这边
This way, this way.
啊 是死胡同 往这走 这边!
Ahh, dead end. Other way, other way!
杰克!
Jack!
杰克 刚才的尝试很勇敢 论苦劳给你满分
That was good try, Jack. "A" For effort.
他变强了 我赢不了他
He's stronger. I can't beat him.
喔!
Aw!
我这么大费周章 全因为一个小男孩
All this fuss over one little boy,
到现在还不改信念
and still he refuses to stop believing.
很好 反正有的是办法
Very well. There are other ways
灭掉光点
to snuff out a light.
你想杀他 先过我这一关
If you want him, you're gonna have to go through me.
看你毛茸茸的样
Look how fluffy you are.
我来给你挠挠耳朵吧?
Would you like a scratch behind the ears?
你休想
Don't you even think about it.
看到你们现在这个样子
I can't tell you how happy it makes me
我不知道有多开心
to see you all like this.
你们看起来糟透了
You look awful.
杰克 我害怕
Jack. I'm scared.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
但你不会有事的
But you're gonna be all right.
我们来玩些好玩的
We're gonna have a little fun instead.
没错! 这就是我的专长!
That's it! That's my center!
你感觉如何 杰米?
So what do you think, Jamie?
现在相信食虫人了吗...
Do you believe in the Boogey...
我们去找你的朋友
Now let's go get your friends.
哦!
Ohh!
哇!
Whoa!
棒极了!
Cool!
哦
Oh.
杰米 你怎么会飞?
Jamie, how are you doing that?
是杰克冻人! 快起来 我们需要你帮忙!
Jack Frost! Come on, we need your help!
那是...
Hey, is that...
杰克冻人!
Jack Frost!
啊?
Huh?
圣诞快乐!  复活节快乐!
Merry Christmas! Happy Easter!
吃完糖别忘了用牙线清洁牙齿!
Don't forget to floss!
小蛋糕?  什么?
Cupcake? What?
杰米 你说对了!
Jamie, you were right!
真的有复活节兔子!
The Easter Bunny's real!
还有牙仙!  还有圣诞老人!
The Tooth Fairy! And Santa!
他们都是真的!
They're all real!
喔! 耶!
Whoo! Yeah!
你们觉得几个孩子能助你们打败它们?
You think a few children can help you? Against this?
这只是噩梦而已 杰米
They're just bad dreams, Jamie.
我来保护你 伙计
And we'll protect you, mate.
你保护他们?
Aw, you'll protect them?
那谁来保护你啊?
But who will protect you?
我来
I will.
我来  我来
I will. I will.
还有我
And me.
我试试吧
I'll try.
现在还不相信食虫人是真的吗?
Still think there's no such thing as the Boogeyman?
我相信你是真的 但我不怕你
I do believe in you. I'm just not afraid of you.
啊?
Huh?
耶 牙仙!
Yeah, Tooth Fairy!
好棒!
A-ha!
哦 耶!
Oh. Yeah!
不! 抓住他们!
No! Get them!
看你们的了!
DO your jobs!
快变身 快变身
Oh, yeah, come on, come on.
妈呀!
Oh, crikey!
不可能吧!
No way!
我只是个小兔子!
I'm just a bunny!
你好 伙计
G'day, mate.
喔!
Whoa!
冲啊! 喔... 吼!
Come on! Whoo-hoo!
干掉他们!
Let's get them!
一块上啊 朋友们 我们能行!
Come on, guys, we can do it!
留给你了 伙计
It's all ours, mate.
谢谢 牙牙
Thanks, Tooth.
哦 哦
Ho, ho, ho.
来错屋顶了
Wrong roof.
看这!
Look at that!
我明白了!
I got it!
我知道我们该怎么做了 朋友们 跟我来
I know what we have to do. Guys, come on.
结束了 食虫人
It's over, Pitch.
你无处可逃了
There's no place to hide.
杰克 小心!
Jack, look out!
沙人!
The Sandman!
伙计 你来的真是时候
Mate, you are a sight for sore eyes.
嗯
Hmm.
漂漂!
Pretty!
你的专长?
Your center?
啊?
Hmm?
用了一些时间
It took a while,
最后终于明白了
but I figured it out.
哦...  哦!
Oh... Oh!
你们这些捣蛋鬼!
You're all on naughty list!
兔子 接招!
Bunny, think fast!
不
No.
你们竟敢当着我的面打闹?
You dare have fun in my presence?
我可是人人害怕的食虫人!
I am the Boogeyman and you will fear me!
不! 不
No! No.
这么快就走啊?
Leaving the party so soon?
还没说再见呢
You didn't even say goodbye.
硬币?
A quarter?
这一拳是为我的小精灵打的
And that's for my fairies.
你们消灭不了我的! 永远不会
You can't get rid of me! Not forever.
恐惧不会消失
There will always be fear.
那又怎么样? 只要还有一个孩子相信我们
So what? As long as one child believes,
我们就会和恐惧战斗到底
we will be here to fight fear.
真的吗? 那他们在这干什么呢?
Really? Then what are they doing here?
他们肯定不是我的噩梦 我不害怕
They can't be my Nightmares. I'm not afraid.
看起来是他们闻到的是你的恐惧
Looks like it's your fear they smell.
不 不!
No, no, no. No!
不!
No!
杰克 你准备好了吗? 正式成为守护者
Are you ready now, Jack? To make it official.
现在是宣誓仪式
Then is time you take Oath.
杰克冻人 你愿意
Will you, Jack Frost,
宣誓守护全世界的孩子
vow to watch over the children of the world,
用你的生命去守护
to guard them with your life,
他们的希望 奇迹和梦想吗?
their hopes, their wishes, and their dreams,
孩子是我们拥有的一切 我们为他们而生
for they are all that we have, all that we are,
直到永远
and all that we will ever be?
我愿意
I will.
那恭喜你 因为你已经
Then, congratulations, Jack Frost, for you are now,
永远成为了
and forevermore,
一名守护者
a Guardian.
好样的
That's my boy.
别太激动了 姑娘们
Keep it together, girls.
伙计们 看!
You guys, look!
那是圣诞老人的雪橇  哇 真的有!
That's Santa's sleigh. Wow, it's real!
你们看见了吗?
You guys see that?
人人都爱雪橇
Everyone loves the sleigh.
看看那个!
Wow, look at that!
该走了
Time to go.
太漂亮了
It's beautiful.
复活节快乐 小不点
Happy Easter, you little ankle-biter.
我会想念你的
I'm gonna miss you.
再见 兔子
Bye-bye, Bunny.
你们要走了吗?
You're leaving?
食虫人再来怎么办?
But what if Pitch comes back?
如果我们又不信守护者了怎么办? 如果看不到你们...
What if we stop believing again? If I can't see you...
别担心 别担心
Hey, slow down, slow down.
我告诉你
You're telling me you stop
难道太阳出来以后 你就不相信月亮了吗
believing in the moon when the sun comes up?
不是
No.
那当乌云遮住太阳
Okay. Well, do you stop believing in the sun
你就不相信太阳了吗?
when clouds block it out?
不
No.
杰米 我们从未离开
We'll always be there, Jamie. And now,
我们会一直在这
we'll always be here.
它也会使你成为一名守护者的
Which kind of makes you a Guardian, too.
杰克!
Jack!
驾!
Yah!
我叫杰克冻人
My name is Jack Frost.
我是一名守护者
And I'm a Guardian.
我怎么知道的?
How do I know that?
月亮告诉我的
Because the moon told me so.
所以当月亮告诉你一些事
So when the moon tells you something,
那就相信吧
believe it.